# Vincent Winkeler

Vince@winkeler.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vwinkeler/

Executive leader with demonstrated ability to deliver transformational and innovative technology platforms and solutions. Creates value by understanding business and clinical strategies and objectives, organizational functions, and operational processes and applying expertise across all areas of information technology with emphasis on data, analytics, and applications. Driven and committed to organizational and client partner success, outstanding performance, and exceptional service. Simplifies complexity and provides strong communication at all levels of the organization. Uses thoughtful analysis, creative thinking, and diligent planning to deliver new capabilities and optimize existing practices. Builds successful teams by finding and growing talent, building trust and strong collaborative relationships, creating vision and setting clear direction, and developing collaborative professional culture.

# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

-Strategic Planning

-IT Operations and Management

-IT Financial Management

-Process Improvement

-Cybersecurity Strategy & Management

-People Management

-Policy and Procedure Management

-Solution Delivery

-IT Services Management

-Cloud infrastructure Management

-Data Governance

-Competitive Analysis

-Acquisition Integration

-Contracts, Agreements & Documentation

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### NewGround. Saint Louis. MO

Senior Vice President of Information Technology

Spearheaded the information technology strategy and operations for a \$125 million global design-build construction company to integrate and automate systems. Due to proven results, expertise, and leadership skills, promoted multiple times and given additional responsibilities leading a team of six. Served on the core leadership team, leading the company's direction.

- Improved connectivity by implementing SD-WAN
- Oversaw crisis management, business continuity, and security teams
- Migrated to Microsoft Teams phone system
- Opened, relocated, and closed numerous offices domestically and internationally
- Converted server volumes to SharePoint
- Sponsored cloud-based architectural engineering and construction software to eliminate VPNs
- Software as a service technical specifications software

#### NewGround/Adrenaline Saint Louis. MO

5/2009 ~ 5/2018

5/2018 ~ 12/2023

#### Vice President of Information Technology

Responsible for defining strategy, designing and delivering operational / technology / digital business solutions to support the growth and development of a 3–5 year strategic IT plan defining services aligned with business needs. including IT asset inventory with theft recovery/life cycle asset management and contracts.

- Formulated IT policies, guidelines, standards, and procedures to use technology and data resources efficiently
- Moved co-location datacenter
- Managed the software developer of customer portal websites and administrator of digital signage products
- Project-managed implantation of VMware ESXi, VCenter, and HP Nimble storage area network
- Implemented enterprise-wide switches, and 802.11 A.B.G.N wireless upgrades
- Migrated on-premise exchange to Office 365

- Moved satellite office locations, expanded office footprints, and opened and closed offices
- Divested the company's information technology assets after the sale of Adrenaline

# NewGround Saint Louis, MO

9/2003 ~ 5/2009

#### Director of Information Technology

Crafted and led the strategic transformation of the Information Technology Department, evolving from a part-time production intermediary into a comprehensive, full-time operation focused on customer service. Brought standardization and reliability to the company's technology systems and applied industry best practices for a multitude of software systems (Autodesk/AutoCAD applications, eight different Adobe applications, Sketch Up, three different rendering engines, a CRM System, Smartsheets, DocuSign, back-end office system, etc.).

- Migrated Groupwise and Novell servers to Microsoft Exchange and Windows servers, implementing enterprise virus spam protection and network monitoring Syslog server
- Relocated the main headquarters to 32k square feet of leased office space and many satellite office moves, designing the Data Centers throughout, as well as Colocation datacenters
- Chaired the implementation team for two enterprise business system changes
- Implemented enterprise-wide, international, MPLS wide area network and Cisco voice over IP phone systems
- Devised policy, procedures, and disaster recovery plan

# Quebecor-World Saint Louis, MO

9/1988 -9/2003

#### Systems Engineer

As the Systems Engineer for a manufacturing facility, I drove IT strategies, deployments, and support, proactively working with managers to identify and execute improved technology uses to reduce costs and increase productivity. Promoted multiple times from an Electrician to a Microsoft-Certified Systems Engineer due to proven results and expertise.

- Migrated Domino Server applications to Exchange with fax integration
- Integrated Unix and Novell servers with Microsoft
- Unified the UNIX, Mac, and PLC system production operations with the business systems networks to facilitate information and resource sharing
- Relocated 400,000-square-foot manufacturing information systems operations to a new location
- Configured and installed multiple processor Intel and Alpha Servers, distributed applications, and installed workstations
- Implemented Maintenance Pro database that organized equipment, parts, preventative maintenance schedules, purchases, and work orders

#### PROFICIENT TECHNICAL SKILLS:

MS Office 365
Google Suite
Virtual collaboration Software (MS Teams, Slack, Zoom, etc.)
Windows Server and Active Directory
SQL Server
VMWare
Cisco IOS

#### **EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS, & TRAINING:**

Microsoft Certified System Engineer (MCSE)
Microsoft Certified System Engineer Plus Internet (MCSE+I)
Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)
Cisco Meraki CMNO Training
ISO Train the Trainer Certified

<u>COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT</u> Vice President of 1,400 members 501c7 Non-profit Wreaths Across America; Volunteer Wreath Layer National Weather Service; Weather Spotter Habitat for Humanity
Amateur Radio Operator
Photographer